Flamme.
（フリーレン）フランメ
（フランメ）“先生”
You mean "Master."
何だ？
What is it?
Do you really think it's unfair?
（フリーレン）先生は
本当に卑怯(ひきょう)だと思ってるの？
（フランメ）フリーレン
Frieren, do you remember Basalt's last words?
バザルトの最期の言葉は
覚えてるか？
No.
覚えてない
Their kind uses words only to deceive humans.
あいつらは 言葉で
人間を たぶらかすんだよ
That's right.
そうだ
やつらは言葉を話すだけの
魔物にすぎない
They're nothing more than monsters
capable of speech.
That's the true nature of the
creatures I call demons.
それが 私が
魔族と呼ぶ者たちの正体だ
They don't play fair,
so we must be even more unfair.
やつらは卑怯だ
ならば 私たちは
それ以上の卑怯者になればいい
If it allows me to exterminate demonkind,
then I will gladly embrace this dishonor.
それで 魔族を
根絶やしにできるのなら
私は喜んで その汚名を着よう
♪～
Like a fairy tale
It's a sign the story has reached its end
Like a single passage taken from
A journey that was too long
Of the evil that once cast a shadow
Across this land
And the memories of the short journey
With the hero who defeated it
Beyond Journey's End
The story ends
And the hero goes to sleep
Leaving this land with
Days of peace and quiet
The passage of time heartlessly
Makes people forget
Even the tracks left behind by his life
Begin to rust
Just the same
Your words and wishes and courage
Are still inside of me
And they live on
We chose the same path
That's all it was supposed to be
Why is it that at some point
I wanted to understand the reason for
The tears that fall down my cheeks
Even now
If I retrace the journey we walked together
Even though you're not there
I know I'll be able to find it
～♪
Episode 10: A Powerful Mage
The bleeding won't stop.
（リュグナー）出血が止まらん
This is the end.
ここまでか
Your plan has failed.
（フェルン）これで
あなたたちの計画は
失敗です
You're right.
（リュグナー）そうだな
だが フリーレンは
無事では済むまい
But Frieren won't escape unscathed.
やつは今頃
アウラ様と戦っているはずだ
She must be fighting Lady Aura by now.
Previously, we were forced to
retreat by the party of heroes.
前回は 勇者一行のせいで
撤退を余儀なくされたが
今は もう彼女を守る勇者たちは
存在しない
But this time, there are
no heroes to protect her.
It's true that Frieren is a threat to us,
確かにフリーレンは我らの脅威だ
but she has far less mana than Lady Aura.
だが 魔力は
アウラ様に遠く及ばず
正面から戦えば
フリーレンは必ず負ける
If she engages her directly,
Frieren will lose.
Then Frieren will win.
（フェルン）
なら フリーレン様が勝ちますね
あの人は魔族と
正面から戦うようなマネは
She'd never directly engage a demon.
絶対にしません
必ず アウラを欺いて殺します
I know she'll trick Aura and kill her.
Nonsense.
（リュグナー）バカな
いつだって やつ…
Frieren the Slayer has always
engaged us directly.
葬送のフリーレンは
我らを正面から…
何だ この違和感は…
Why do I feel like something is wrong?
This girl's mana is weak,
小娘の脆弱(ぜいじゃく)な魔力
私は確かに こいつの迅速な魔法の
物量に押しきられた
and yet I was overwhelmed by the
sheer number of her rapid attacks.
But how was she able to do that
without exhausting her mana?
だが なぜ 魔力切れを起こさず
そんな芸当ができた？
I understand now. Is that even possible?
そうか…
まさか そんなことが…
So Frieren does the same.
フリーレンも同じなんだな
卑怯者め
What you've done isn't fair.
You're a disgrace to all mages.
お前たちは魔法使いの
風上にも置けない
（フェルン）それは フリーレン様が
一番 よく分かっていることです
Ms. Frieren knows that better than anyone.
（攻撃音）
ひでえありさまだな
What a dreadful sight.
Looks like an elf village.
エルフの集落か
Basalt the Throne,
玉座のバザルト
魔王軍の将軍の１人だな
a general of the Demon King's army.
軍勢を率いて
集落を潰しに来たってところか
He must've led his forces here
to destroy this village.
Are you the one who killed him?
You seem nearly dead yourself.
こいつを殺したのは お前か？
そこの死にかけ
すごい魔力だ
That's a lot of mana.
You must be powerful.
魔族と正面から戦ったのか
Did you engage the demons directly?
What a fool you are.
くだらねえ　とんだバカだな
Why do people always engage
their enemies directly?
どうして 正面から戦いたがるかね
逃げる 隠れる 不意打ちする
Run, hide, take your enemies by surprise...
いくらでも選択肢はあるだろうが
There are plenty of other options.
I'll never understand strong mages.
強い魔法使いの気持ちは
分からねえ
（フリーレン）分かるはずだ
But you do.
（フランメ）は？
What?
You should understand how I feel...
（フリーレン）あなたには
私の気持ちが分かるはずだ
because you're a far more powerful mage.
あなたのほうが
はるかに強い魔法使いだから
どうして そう思った？
What makes you say that?
Just a feeling.
（フリーレン）何となく
（フランメ）お前 名前は？
What's your name?
What happened to the village?
（フリーレン）
集落は どうなったの？
（フランメ）全滅だ
Its people are dead, down to
the last woman and child.
女子供も皆殺し
I was the strongest, but I still
couldn't protect them.
守れなかった
私が一番 強かったのに
You really are a fool.
本当にバカだな
私が お前の立場なら
迷わず逃げていた
If I'd been in your shoes,
I wouldn't have hesitated to run.
Put me down.
（フリーレン）下ろして
（フランメ）下ろさない
No.
お前には才能がある
私の弟子にする
You have potential.
You're going to be my apprentice.
それに分かっているはずだ
And you know you wouldn't have survived
if I hadn't happened upon you.
私が通りかからなければ
お前は死んでいた
On top of failing to protect the village,
you nearly died yourself.
お前は集落も守れなかった上に
死ぬところだったんだ
Your death truly would've been in vain.
文字どおり ムダ死にだ
追っ手だな
We're being pursued.
ん？
（フランメ）
お前が殺した将軍より強いぞ
They're stronger than the general you killed.
Interesting creatures, aren't they?
面白いよな こいつら
直前まで魔力を完全に消して
They had every intention
of catching us off guard
闇討ちする気 満々だったくせに
by concealing their mana
until just before they struck,
こっちが魔法使いと
分かるやいなや
but the moment they realized we were mages,
they stepped out into the open.
堂々と姿を現しやがった
They're cunning and they don't play fair,
こいつらは
卑怯で狡猾(こうかつ)だが
同時に
どいつもこいつも
but every last one of them has a ridiculous
sense of pride when it comes to magic.
くだらねえ魔法への誇りを
持っていやがる
Human mage, leave the elf girl and go.
（魔族）人間の魔法使い
そのエルフの女を置いていけ
（フランメ）そうしたら
見逃してくれんのか？
Will you let me go if I do?
（魔族）エルフを皆殺しにしろ
"Kill all the elves."
それが魔王様の命令だ
Those were the Demon King's orders.
お前の命など どうでもいい
Your life matters not to me.
そうかい
I see.
フリーレン
Frieren, it's true that I'm painfully aware
of what it's like to be a powerful mage.
確かに私は
強い魔法使いの気持ちが
痛いほど よく分かる
こいつらの気持ちも
手に取るように分かるさ
I know exactly how these creatures feel, too.
I know the absolute confidence they
have in the magics they've studied.
今まで 研鑽(けんさん)してきた⸺
自らの魔法に対する自信と信頼
In other words, they're stupidly
proud and overconfident.
要するに クソみたいな
驕(おご)りと油断だ
（地響き）
Frieren, unlike you,
they judged me a weakling.
（フランメ）フリーレン
お前と違って こいつらは
私を雑魚と判断したらしい
Though they were exceptional mages,
their overconfidence cost them their lives.
こいつらは格上の
卓越した魔法使いだったが
ささいな油断で命を落とした
You hid your strength by controlling
how much mana you release.
体外に放出する魔力を制限して
強さを誤認させた
（フランメ）そうだ
That's right.
相手が認識した魔力の誤差で
欺いて殺す
Deceive and kill your enemies by allowing
them to miscalculate your strength.
It's a cowardly and unfair way to fight
that makes a mockery of magic.
誇り高き魔法を愚弄した
卑怯で最低な戦い方だ
（ドアが閉まる音）
Your injuries are looking a lot better.
（フランメ）
傷も だいぶよくなってきたな
（座る音）
Shall we begin your training?
そろそろ 修行を始めるか
Flamme.
（フリーレン）フランメ
“先生”だ
You mean "Master."
Demons took everything from me.
（フリーレン）
私は魔族に すべてを奪われた
Me, too.
（フランメ）私もだ
I hate them so much that I wish
I could exterminate every last one.
（フリーレン）
魔族を根絶やしにしたいほど憎い
Me, too.
（フランメ）私もだ
けれども 私は魔法が好きで
But I love magic.
私も好きだ
So do I.
Which is why only you and I should become
cowards who make a mockery of magic.
だから
魔法を愚弄するような卑怯者は
私たちだけでいい
What should I do to train?
（フリーレン）
修行って何をすればいいの？
（フランメ）体外に放出する魔力を
10分の１以下に抑えてみろ
Try limiting the mana you release
to one-tenth of its normal volume.
Impressive. You're controlling it well.
さすがだな　よく制御できている
（フリーレン）この程度
エルフなら 誰でもできるよ
Any elf can do this.
（フランメ）
あとは並行して 基本訓練だ
While you do that, we'll work on your
fundamentals and raise your base mana level.
基礎的な魔力を上げていく
（フリーレン）
それだけでいいの？
That's all?
（フランメ）簡単だろ？
Simple, right?
ところで この魔力の制限は
どのくらい 続ければいいの？
By the way, how long should
I keep suppressing my mana?
あまり長いと疲れるんだけど
It starts to get tiring
if I do it for too long.
（フランメ）私と同じくらい
As long as I do.
For life.
一生だ
You'll spend your entire life fooling demons.
お前は一生を懸けて
魔族を欺くんだ
（アウラ）
リュグナーが死んだわね
Lügner is dead.
Now all your executioners
have been eliminated.
（フリーレン）
これで 首切り役人は全滅だ
失敗したね アウラ
You've failed, Aura.
You're right. It's a shame.
そうね　残念だわ
But if I can defeat you here,
then it won't have been for nothing.
でも ここで
あなたを しとめられれば
戦果としては十分
In this battle, you've released numerous
immortal soldiers from my control.
あなたは この戦いで
たくさんの不死の軍勢を
私の支配下から解放したわね
Was it wise to expend so much mana against me?
この私の前で
そんなに多くの魔力を消費して
大丈夫なのかしら？
The Scales of Obedience.
（フリーレン）服従の天秤(てんびん)
天秤に互いの魂を乗せ
When two souls are placed on the scale,
より魔力の大きいほうが
相手を服従させる
whichever has more mana
forces the other to submit.
Aura can only use such a risky spell
because of her tremendous amount of mana.
こんなリスクの高い魔法を
扱えるのは
アウラの絶大な魔力が
あってのこと
Generally speaking,
魔力は基本的に
鍛錬を積み重ねた年月に比例して
増加していく
a person's mana increases in proportion
with the time spent training.
I can feel it in the mana pouring off Aura.
あふれ出すアウラの魔力から
伝わってくる
She's a great demon who has lived
for over five hundred years,
アウラが500年以上 生きた
大魔族であること
その生涯のほとんどを
鍛錬に費やしたこと
and she's spent most of her life training.
Five hundred years, huh?
500年か
That's fairly long-lived for a demon.
魔族の中でも かなりの長寿だ
I doubt she's been challenged before.
今まで敵なしだったのだろう
I can learn so much just from
the mana flowing off her.
体外の魔力の量だけでも
これだけの情報が手に入る
Regardless, demons don't conceal
their mana—nor can they.
それでも 魔族は
魔力を包み隠さないし
包み隠せない
A pity.
Auserlese.
アゼリューゼ
Master.
（フリーレン）先生
（フランメ）うん？
Demons are cunning, aren't they?
（フリーレン）
魔族って ずる賢いんだよね
なんで 先生みたいに
Why don't they constantly suppress
their mana like you do?
常に魔力を
制限したりしないんだろう
フッ… できねえのさ
They can't.
魔族は個人主義の世界といっても
Demons are individualists,
人類と戦うための
but they form the barest connections
needed to fight against humankind.
最低限の組織的なつながりを
持っている
組織に必要なものって
何だと思う？
What do you think an organization
needs to function?
Order?
秩序かな
（フランメ）そうだ
That's right.
要は 組織をまとめる
偉いやつが必要ってことだ
In other words, you need someone
important to lead an organization.
人の場合は…
In the case of humans,
例えば この国の連中は
importance is determined by status
and wealth, like they do in this nation.
地位や財産で偉いやつが決まる
あの宮殿から出てきた
身なりのいいのが偉いやつだ
That well-dressed man exiting
that palace is a man of importance.
It's hard to tell which humans are important,
人の偉さは分かりづらい
だから ああやって着飾って
見た目で分かるようにするんだ
so they dress themselves up
to make it obvious.
魔族は違うの？
Demons are different?
（フランメ）やつらは
自分たちが魔物だった頃と
They haven't changed a bit
since they were monsters.
何も変わっていない
強いやつが偉いんだ
Might makes right.
人より ずっと分かりやすい
It's far easier to understand than humans.
You can tell who's strong
just by looking at them.
強さってのは見れば分かる
魔力だね
You mean mana.
（フランメ）
やつらにとっての魔力は
Mana is to them what status
and wealth are for humans.
人にとっての地位や財産だ
It's dignity itself.
尊厳そのものと言ってもいい
They may temporarily suppress
their mana for the sake of stealth,
隠密の手段として
一時的に
魔力を制限することはあっても
常日頃から 魔力を
制限するバカなんて存在しない
but none are foolish enough
to suppress their mana all the time.
どこぞの貴族が
お忍びで城下町に下りてくるのと
It's the difference between a noble
sneaking out into town incognito
and that same noble debasing themselves by
abandoning their status and wealth entirely.
地位も財産も捨てて
身を落とすのとじゃ⸺
まったく違う話だろ？
The world of demons is cruel.
そして 魔力の低い連中に
尊厳が与えられるほど
They'd never grant any dignity
to those with little mana.
魔族の世界は甘くない
だから 力の強い魔族ほど
必死に魔力を誇示するんだ
So the stronger they are, the more desperate
they are to show off their mana.
For them, there's no benefit to
constantly suppressing their mana.
やつらにとっては
常に魔力を制限するメリットなんて
皆無だし
そもそも そんな発想すらない
It doesn't even occur to them to do it.
It's a pity, isn't it?
哀れだよな
人が 地位や財産に
縛られるように
Just as humans are bound by status
and wealth, demons are bound by mana.
魔族は
魔力に縛られている
やつらは魔法を誇りに思い
Despite their pride in
and unparalleled love for magic,
誰よりも魔法が好きなのに
they can't control their own mana.
己の魔力すら自由にできない
Frieren, you're lucky you're not a demon.
フリーレン
魔族じゃなくてよかったな
You're right. I wouldn't be able
to deceive them if I were.
そうだね　おかげで魔族を欺ける
It's been three years since you
started suppressing your mana.
（フランメ）
魔力の制限を始めてから３年か
私の見込みは
間違っていなかったな
Looks like I was right about you.
You've grown much better at that.
だいぶ 様になってきたな
Frieren, do you still love magic?
フリーレン　まだ魔法は好きか？
Where did that come from, Master?
突然 どうしたの 先生
Somewhat, I suppose.
ほどほどかな
Long ago, you once confidently
answered that you loved magic.
お前は ずっと昔
魔法が好きだと はっきり答えた
（フリーレン）
たった50年前でしょ
That was only fifty years ago.
You're right.
そうだな
結局 私は お前に
戦いのことしか教えなかった
In the end, all I could do
was teach you to fight.
復讐(ふくしゅう)のための魔法だ
Magic for revenge.
Do you regret it?
後悔しているの？
いいや
No. I'm glad I taught my magic to you.
お前に 私の魔法を託して
よかったと思っている
お前の長い寿命なら
Given how long you'll live,
いつか 魔王を倒せるほどの高みに
たどり着ける
you might eventually become strong
enough to defeat the Demon King.
Frieren, I have one request.
フリーレン　ひとつ頼みがある
What is it?
（フリーレン）何？
（フランメ）
私の墓の周りは花畑にしてくれ
Plant flowers around my grave.
That doesn't seem like you.
（フリーレン）似合わないね
（フランメ）そうだな
I know.
Frieren, my favorite spell
creates a field of beautiful flowers.
フリーレン
私の一番 好きな魔法は
きれいな花畑を出す魔法だ
小さい頃 両親が教えてくれてな
My parents taught it to me when I was little.
魔法が好きになった きっかけだ
It's what made me love magic.
Huh.
（フリーレン）ふーん…
Teach me that spell.
その魔法 教えてよ
いいか フリーレン
Listen to me, Frieren.
歴史に名を残そうなんて
考えるなよ
You must never seek to leave
your name in history.
目立たず生きろ
Live in obscurity.
お前が歴史に名を残すのは
You won't leave your name in history
until you defeat the Demon King.
魔王を ぶっ殺す時だ
（ヒンメル）この森に
I've heard there's a long-lived
mage in these woods.
長く生きた魔法使いが
いると聞いた
Are you her?
それは 君か？
I've lived a long time, but I haven't
done much with my life.
（フリーレン）
長く生きたといっても
だらだら生きていただけだよ
I'm not exceptional.
優秀なわけじゃない
（アイゼン）ふむ…
Huh. What do you think, Heiter?
どう思う？　ハイター
（ハイター）うーん…
She has roughly one-fifth of my mana.
魔力は私の５分の１くらいですね
It's not bad.
まあまあといったところです
Who's this irritating guy?
（フリーレン）
何だ こいつ ムカつくな
Leave. You don't have business
with a mediocre mage, do you?
帰りなよ
まあまあの魔法使いに
用はないでしょ
（ヒンメル）いや
No, you're stronger than
any mage I've ever met.
君は 僕が出会ってきた
どの魔法使いよりも強い
What makes you say that?
どうして そう思うの？
Just a feeling.
何となくだ
Auserlese.
（アウラ）アゼリューゼ
You seem happy, Aura.
（フリーレン）
うれしそうだね アウラ
勝利を確信しているの？
Are you certain you'll win?
You'll see.
今に分かるわ
Frieren the Slayer.
葬送のフリーレン
80年ほど前に
初めて表舞台に姿を現し
You made your first major
appearance eighty years ago.
勇者一行と共に
魔王様を倒した⸺
With the party of heroes,
you defeated the Demon King.
謎に満ちた
年齢不詳のエルフの魔法使い
You're a mysterious elven mage
whose age is unknown.
But it doesn't matter how
long-lived a mage you are.
でも あなたが どれだけ
長く生きた魔法使いかなんて
どうでもいい
Your mana tells me everything
I need to know.
あなたの魔力が
すべてを物語っている
I can see it quite clearly.
手に取るように分かる
あなたは
優秀な魔法使いだけれども
You're an exceptional mage,
but your mana itself is unimpressive.
魔力自体は それほどでもない
鍛錬を積んだのは
せいぜい 合わせて100年程度
You can't have had more than a
hundred years or so of training.
しかも 80年前と
大して変わっていない
Not only that, but you've barely
changed since eighty years ago.
魔力以外の技術を磨いていたのか
Were you honing other skills
instead of working on your mana?
それとも
だらだらと生きていたのか
Or were you simply wasting your life away?
Either way, you are no match for me.
どちらにせよ
私には遠く及ばない
I win.
私の勝ちよ
あとは この私直々(じきじき)に
あなたの首を落としてあげる
All that's left is to sever your head myself.
It wasn't even necessary
to exhaust Frieren's mana.
これなら フリーレンの魔力を
消耗させるまでもなかったわ
I needn't have been so cautious.
少し警戒しすぎた
She defeated many of my
immortal soldiers, too.
不死の軍勢も
だいぶ やられちゃったし
あとで補充しないと…
I'll have to replenish their numbers later.
ん？
What's this?
何だ？
The scales are starting to tip toward Frieren.
天秤が フリーレンのほうに
傾いていく
（フリーレン）私の魂を
天秤に乗せたな アウラ
You placed my soul on the scales, Aura.
正直 このまま
軍勢の物量で押されていたら
Honestly, I would've been in trouble
if you'd tried to overwhelm me with numbers.
危なかったけれども
I'm glad you're so confident in your own mana.
お前が 自分の魔力に
自信を持っていてよかった
Now I can finally defeat you.
やっと お前を倒せる
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
もう気がついているはずだ
You should've figured it out by now.
I've been suppressing my mana.
私は魔力を制限していた
You misjudged the situation, Aura.
お前は見誤ったんだ アウラ
That's impossible. That wouldn't
have escaped my notice.
そんなはずはないわ
それなら この私が
見逃すはずがない
There was no hint of the instability
or variation in mana output
あなたの魔力には
制限特有の不安定さも
わずかなブレもなかった
that comes with suppression.
I'm surprised. Demons are capable
of observing mana that precisely?
驚いた
魔族は そこまで正確に
魔力を観測できるのか
Sounds like my master made the
right call with her methods.
先生のやり方は
正しかったみたいだ
I've spent most of my life
suppressing my mana.
私は生きてきた時間のほとんどを
魔力を制限して過ごした
This state has become natural for me.
この状態が自然になるほどに
バカじゃないの？
Are you stupid? Why would you
do something so pointless?
なんで そんな
訳の分からないこと…
そうだね　バカみたいだ
You're right. It's stupid.
But it lets me beat your kind.
でも お前たちに勝てる
（アウラ）ふざけるな
This is absurd.
I'm a great demon who's lived
for over five hundred years.
私は500年以上 生きた大魔族だ
アウラ　お前の前にいるのは
Aura, the person standing before you...
is a mage who's lived
for over a thousand years.
千年以上 生きた
魔法使いだ
Frieren.
（フランメ）フリーレン
Just as demons deceive humankind with words,
魔族が言葉で人を欺くように
お前は魔力で魔族を欺くんだ
you must use your mana to deceive demons.
Aura,
（フリーレン）アウラ　自害しろ
kill yourself.
Impossible.
ありえない…
H-How could I...?
この私が…
（倒れる音）
♪～
And you alright
Can you hear me
Trailing along deserted train tracks
Crying excessively
Wanting you to smile
I hold on to memories I'd like to keep fresh
There's something I'd like to tell you
With words more precious than a goodbye
Unremarkable yet special
See, things that couldn't have been
Seen if it weren't for these eyes
Why? They begin to overflow
So, if I were to be born again
I would surely choose this place once more
So, if we were to meet again
I'd never let you go, I'd choose the present
Even if no promises were made
Even if I'm lost in days of loneliness
Those tears will be alright,
dawn will surely break
I'm whispering our lullaby
～♪
for you to come back home
Do you have someone to praise you?
You're traveling to heaven, then?
I'm not sure I understand...
You've got a nice body, old man.
The largest magical city in the
northern lands, Äußerst.
What's a first-class mage?
What is that trinket?
It means we're elves.
Episode 11
Winter in the Northern Lands
It's the winters of the northern lands.